the lesson lives within the question.
A Loy.
For years you've trained to win the proving, but only for yourself as a brave It will be your duty to fight for your tribe.
My tribe?
You said I wouldn't need them.
But I never said the tribe wouldn't be you.
Dawn has passed.
This will be your last day in the embraces.
An outcast.
Use the time to set your mind on the challenges before you.
When it is time for you to go to mother's heart, I'll be waiting for you along the way.
I understand the final lesson roster.
Do you?
But if I'm going to stand for something, it'll have to be something I believe in.
Then I hope you find it a line.
I hope you do.
Okay.
What?
You can stop
this old last.
It's heavy.
It's coming, right?
Yeah,
You.
Who are you calling out for?
Do you need help?
I have nothing against outcasts.
Far from it.
But I shouldn't talk to you.
I don't want to get in trouble.
I don't see anyone else around to help.
I guess you're right.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be callous.
My brother was cast out what his sentence has ended.
He he should have come home, but he didn't.
And each day I cut a notch on the wall.
So I knew Bram sentence was over.
Then I cut three more, but he still hadn't come back.
I begged the matriarchs to send braves to find him.
And all they found was a blood soaked camp.
The Braves that he must be dead.
But I have to know the truth.
So I came out looking for him.
All I can think about is what might have happened.
Is he really dead?
Or maybe just wounded?
Is he suffering?
Does he need help?
I can't stand it.
Not knowing why was your brother cast out?
Rome was always a little different, A little touched.
One of the hunters had a cruel heart and never let him alone.
I was gone, but now earn The hunter said after him, like always.
But this time, bomb struck back with a rock and split the man's skull.
Spirits made him do it, he said whispers of the for gotten What do you mean for gotten all mother curses?
Blessed femurs who won't repent, banishing them from her eternal memory.
Those lost spirits are the for gotten.
Bram used to say they spoke to him, told him to do things.
It was such a burden for him.
And and there was nothing I could do to help.
I'll do what I can to find your brother.
You will
let me come with you.
I won't be a bother.
I know how to stay out of sight.
I'm faster on my own.
If that is how it must be, just find him then.
Please,
scrapper.
Power cell spark.
A resource can be looted from this component.
Shooting with shock arrows will trigger an explosion.
Electrifying anything in the area Radar Destroying this component disables the scanning ability.
You know
this must be Brahms camp.
Better clear of these watchers.
Okay,
but nobody.
It's gotta be more to this.
Looks like a few drops of blood lead away from the camp.
Who's my business?
Did someone attack Graham with it?
Looks like more blood leading away from here.
Their bucket.
Did someone bring the blood to the camp?
Trail of blood ends here.
Whoever left must have also left Tracks
snow.
It's not getting any warmer out here.
I got one.
You know
that's twisted.
I wonder if the blood from the camp came from this.
If Bram did this, why does he want people to think he's dead?
And why desecrate the shrine?
One of us,
Watcher, whoever I'm falling made short work of it.
If it's Bram, he definitely knows how to handle a spear.
Someone loaded with supplies.
Brown was an outcast for a long time.
Why take food in gear now?
You?
That's the supplies from the cash.
Why would they take them and just throw them away?
Help my son
myself before I hurt her?
Die won't Pleasant.
Uh uh.
Not until you promise.
Good.
She's my sister.
I need to protect her.
I will.
I'll kill myself.
I'll kill myself before I hurt her.
You.
You're not a spirit.
What do you want?
I want you to step away from the edge.
Prom?
No, Leave me alone.
Can't you see I need time to think
How?
How am I supposed to think when everybody is shouting at me so many voices to listen to.
You must make your head hurt.
I promised.
My voice will be soft and soothing.
Soft voice like a Lars It's been so long
years.
Yes.
Yes, I I will.
Listen,
that's better.
Now tell me what's troubling you.
Spirits of the forgotten
souls cursed by the all mother.
There are voices ever.
Let me be.
You want me to do things,
people?
If I go back to the Nora, they might make me hurt.
Olarra and I kill myself before I let that happen.
Do you have to listen to the spirits prop?
They're speaking to me right now.
Oh is with me.
They take care of me, keep me company.
Help me.
Except when they scream.
Like when that hunter knocked me down.
Chris, just go with the rock.
They said
and I did wrong.
You're a life.
Oh, mother, be praised.
I'm sorry I followed you, but I had to make sure he was all right.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, please, sister, I I can't protect you.
I need no protection from you.
How can you be certain?
The voices he hears call for blood, even yours.
But surely he wouldn't hurt his own sister.
I've taken care of him since I was six.
Bram isn't ready to return to the Nora, but I don't think he'll hurt you, Lara.
There's a place where I can stay a cave on all Mother Mountain.
I suppose you could visit me there.
So long as I'm strong, you will be brought.
I'll help you.
Thank you.
A lawyer.
I'll take care of him now.
May you walk in all mother's eternal memory And may the for gotten leave you be?
Yeah.
I'll find a use for you.
Keep quiet.
Now
what?
All right,
but
they need to speak to you.
I'm injured.
I need your help.
You want to talk to an outcast?
I'm desperate for help.
Whatever the consequences.
You know the Matrix might cast you out for speaking to me, don't you?
I don't care.
What's the problem?
In trouble with your leg?
Forget about me.
It's my daughter, Arana.
She's in danger.
She went after a scrap.
Your new mothers cradle I fear for her life.
Why would your daughter hunt a scrapper on her own?
It's my fault.
I went after it First they tore up my leg.
I barely got away If I left a spear impaled in the machine.
That spear was made by Adina, my mate,
who died last year.
It means everything to Iran.
A she She went after the scrapper to get it back.
I'll accept any punishment if it means she's safe.
Please help me set things right.
I'll do what I can to help your daughter.
Make sure she's all right.
I'm picking.
That must be a Rana.
Sounds like she's in trouble.
I'm stuck up here.
I get it.
Huh?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
No,
I just wanna Thank you.
Thank you.
I thought those watchers were gonna tear me apart.
Your father sent me after you.
It's time to go home, I figured.
But I can't go back until I get my mother Spear from that scrapper.
Spear must mean a lot to you.
My mother made it not long before she died.
I can't believe my father lost it.
He didn't mean to.
Scrappers are dangerous.
I know.
It just can't stand the idea that it might be gone forever.
Your father is worried sick about you.
He gets worried if I go 10 steps to relieve myself in the bushes, he just He doesn't want to lose you.
I know, but I do wish you wouldn't yell at me so much.
How did you wind up in that tree?
I tracked the scrapper to mother's cradle.
Caught a glimpse of it too.
But then a watcher saw me and called his pack
my own mother.
I'm just not a good enough hunter to get that spear back, am I?
Look for your spear.
You will.
Thank you.
Go find your father.
His leg gave out while he was searching for you.
Just south of mothers.
No.
Okay, I'll go to him right away.
Thanks again.
Rawness Trail ends here.
Must be where she saw the scrapper.
If I follow its tracks, I should be able to find that spear.
This cradle,
Caroline's here
across the river.
Better cheque.
The other side
there.
Time to get that spear.
You.
It's a well made weapon.
Iran will be happy to have it back.
What is it now?
Always a pleasure doing business.
I guess that concludes our business.
All right.
Good luck in the proving blessing of all mother and all that.
No,
be fascinating if they weren't looking for me
Sing.
What is it?
Back to your business?
I'm gonna need this.
Oh, Mother, be praised.
A lawyer back with fear.
First you send a Rana bag to me, and now you've got the spear.
When I first called out to you for help, I didn't even know if you'd speak to me.
I'm glad you did.
You need to.
I can't believe you got the spear back.
Your mother knew how to craft them.
It's exceptional.
Make.
I'll never be the craft or she wants.
But she did pass along a few tricks.
I'd be happy to take a look at your spear.
Thank you.
It sounds like she was special.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Well, because of you, I still have this beer to remember her by.
You didn't have to help us.
But you did.
She would have admired that.
Thank you, Haley, for everything.